Andrew Kapsa

New York, New York | 915-227-4809 | andrew.kapsa1@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Github | Blog |

Software Engineer

I'm a software engineer with extensive experience in customer and client relations. I am experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming. I have always loved technology and programming since I was a kid. I continue to learn new skills to improve myself. I'm currently learning Python and Next.js. I am learning Next.js to create my portfolio website and I am learning Python to increase my skill set. I have contributed to open source projects through participation in Hacktoberfest 2022. I have skills and experience in teamwork, working under pressure, meeting deadlines, leadership, and time management. I have a strong desire and willingness to learn that will help me to make up for lack of time in the industry. I pride myself on having a moldable personality and being able to work well with anyone. I will always find a way to complete what is asked of me and I won't stop working on it until the job is done.

TECH PROJECTS

News Owl - Github | Demo

News website where a user can see and search for the latest news articles.

- Pulls data from a public API to display news articles and updates
- Allows users to favorite and save articles after a refresh
- Utilizes React and Bootstrap to give a clean and user friendly interface

Corporate Cleaner - Github | Demo

An employee management website where a user can create a list of their employees, managers and more for their company. There are many options to sort through and easily access the specific data of each employee..

- Uses a Ruby backend server with Sintra to support a React frontend app
- Uses many "one to many" relations to connect the different data tables.
- Users have full CRUD features with the employee, manager, and supervisor data

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java, JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, SQL, ActiveRecord, HTML, CSS, react-Bootstrap, Next.is, Python

WORK EXPERIENCE

Swifto New York, New York
Dog Walker 11/2021 - Present

- Meet with talk with clients to get to know them and cater to their pets specific needs
- Take one or multiple dogs for a walk anywhere between 20 to 90 minutes
- Expected to show up and meet specific time windows that the client sets for their pet(s)

Texas Roadhouse El Paso, Texas Busser 03/2021 - 09/2021

- Communicated with hostesses to clean tables quickly and thoroughly to maintain flow of business.
- Heavy lifting up to 60 pounds when taking out trash and carrying tubs for cleaning
- Responsible for maintaining front-of-house and back-of-house cleanliness

ChipotleEl Paso, TexasCrew Member05/2020 - 09/2021

- Handled all transactions between customers while maintaining a friendly attitude
- I kept the lobby and bathroom clean/stocked for customer use.
- Through the use of Microsoft Excel and restaurant computer systems, I counted and handled money at the end of shift to make sure cashbox was correct

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, New York

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Harvard Computer Science Course

New York, New York

Algorithms, data structures, software engineering, C, Python, SQL plus, HTML, CSS, and more